Guide to the Louis Dupree Papers, 1943 - 1989, undated UA.29.02.0037
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Louis Dupree papers
1943-1989 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Dupree, Louis, 1925-
UA.29.02.0037
4.5 Linear Feet
Louis Dupree was a scholar, educator, and consultant on the refugees, politics, and archaeology of Afghanistan and Pakistan. He served as a Senior Research Associate for the Program in Islamic and Arabian Development Studies at Duke University during the late 1980s. The Louis Dupree Papers contain correspondence, notes, clippings, conference programs, drafts, manuscripts, speeches, newsletters, interview transcripts, research materials, teaching materials, a scrapbook, photographs, grant applications, memorabilia, student papers, a dissertation, and other materials related to the personal life and professional career of archaeologist, activist, and scholar Louis Dupree. Major subjects include Louis Dupree, Nancy Hatch Dupree, the Duke University Program in Islamic and Arabian Development Studies, Ralph Braibanti, Afghanistan, Afghan refugees, Afghanistan-Pakistan relations, Pakistan, the United States Army 11th Airborne, the United States Army 187th Airborne, and the United States Military Academy at West Point. English.
Access Restrictions
Access restricted. The subseries entitled Correspondence with Afghan and Pakistani refugees and students is restricted. This series contains sensitive information. Contact Research Services for access: https://duke.qualtrics.com/jfe/form/SV_8fblaT2NbgbQujj
Conditions Governing Access
Access restricted. Some materials in this collection are personnel records. Records pertaining to employment where individuals are identified are closed for 70 years.
Provenance
The Louis Dupree Papers was received by the University Archives as a gift in 1989.
Biographical Note
Louis Dupree was born in Greenville, North Carolina in 1925. He attended Greenville High School until about 1943, enlisting in the armed forces before earning his diploma. He served in World War II, first as a merchant seaman, then as an officer in the 11th Airborne Division in the Philippines campaign and occupation of Japan. Dupree received the Mariner's Medal, Merchant Marine Combat Bar, Combat Infantry Badge, Purple Heart, and Bronze Star.
During 1947 to 1955, Dupree earned his bachelor's, master's, and doctorate degrees in Anthropology from Harvard. He began research in Central and South Asia in 1949. In the United States, Dupree taught and conducted research at Air University, Maxwell Air Force Base, Alabama, from 1953 to 1957. In 1957, he accepted a teaching appointment in the Anthropology Department at Pennsylvania State University. Dupree taught as a Visiting Professor at Kabul University (Afghanistan), Princeton University, and the United States Military Academy at West Point.
From 1959 to 1983, Dupree was a representative of the American Universities Field Staff (AUFS) in Afghanistan and Pakistan. He spent two years researching and writing under the AUFS program, returning to the United States every third year to lecture at the twelve universities sponsoring AUFS. Dupree was also director of several archaeological surveys and excavations in Afghanistan from 1959 to1983, sponsored by American institutions such as the American Museum of Natural History, the National Science Foundation, the American Philosophical Society, and the National Endowment for the Humanities. His excavation on upper Paleolithic sites at Aq Kupruk in northern Afghanistan won international acclaim.
In 1966, Dupree married Nancy Hatch in Afghanistan, whom he had met while she was writing a guidebook of the Bamiyan area of Afghanistan. The Duprees continued to intermittently live and work in Afghanistan.
While on AUFS business in Kabul, Afghanistan just prior to the 1978 Soviet Invasion, Dupree was imprisoned by Afghans and their Soviet advisors. He was interrogated at length about United States intelligence operations and his interactions with Afghans. He was ultimately released through the intervention of Afghan friends. The account of his imprisonment appears as a six-part series, Red Flag over the Hindu Kush in American University Field Staff Reports (1980).
As other nations became interested in the plight of Afghanistan, the Duprees were called upon to advise the parliaments or foreign ministries of Germany, France, Sweden, Norway, England, Austria, Pakistan, and to the United Nations High Commission on Refugees. Dupree frequently corresponded with Pakistan's president, General Mohammed Zia Ul-Haq. In the United States, Dupree acted as a consultant to the State Department, United States Agency for International Development (U.S. AID), the Peace Corps, Esso Pakistan Fertilizer Company, United Nations Development Programs, UNESCO, Helsinki Watch, Amnesty International, the World Bank, and other organizations.
In 1985, after teaching for one year at West Point Military Academy and another year at Princeton University, he joined the Program in Islamic and Arabian Development Studies at Duke University as a Senior Research Associate. He held concurrent appointments at Duke University as Visiting Professor of Anthropology, Political Science, and Public Policy Studies. He also taught at the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill in the departments of Anthropology and Political Science.
The Islamic and Arabian Development Studies Program operated at Duke from 1977 to 1989 under the direction of Professor Ralph Braibanti. It funded the acquisition of library materials that supported its mission, facilitating the accession to the Duke libraries of two major Middle Eastern collections: the Joseph J. Malone Collection on Arabian Affairs and the Louis and Nancy Hatch Dupree Collection on Islamic Inner Asia. The Dupree Collection consists of about 5,000 items, 200 of which are located in the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library. Reflecting the careers and interests of their donors, the materials in the collection focus on the anthropology, art, archaeology, folklore, linguistics, and history of Afghanistan. There are also significant holdings on Islam, the Central Asian Republics, and South Asia.
A social activist, Dupree was Honorary Director and one of the founders of the Afghan Relief Committee. The beneficiaries of the Afghan Relief Committee were primarily Doctors Without Borders, Freedom Medical of Washington, D.C., Aide Medicale International, and Sainte Sud of Marseilles. Dupree was involved with the Afghanistan Action Committee at Duke University and corresponded with members of many other humanitarian assistance organizations.
Dupree and Nancy Hatch Dupree spent years researching and living in Afghanistan and planned to retire there. Together they researched and planned to write a book on Afghan refugees in Pakistan. By 1987, their collaborative work earned them a joint award, the International Rescue Committee's Bronze Medal for Service to Afghanistan Refugees. In 1988, the Duprees returned to Pakistan as Joint Fulbright Senior Scholars. Louis Dupree authored many books and over 200 articles. His articles appeared in various publications such as American Anthropologist, the Middle East Journal, the Economist, the New York Times, the Nation, Evergreen Review, and the Khyber Mail.
Some of the books authored by Dupree include: Afghanistan (1973), Physical Anthropology of Afghanistan (1970), Changing Patterns of Social Structure in Afghanistan (1970), Deh Morasi Ghundai: a Chalcolithic Site in South-Central Afghanistan (1963), and The Desert Survival Field Test (1956).
Louis Dupree died in 1989 at the age of 63. Nancy Hatch Dupree continued her work with Afghan refugees.
Related Material
Biographical Reference Collection: Louis Dupree
Duke University Archives
News Service Biographical Files: Louis Dupree
Duke University Archives
Maheshwary, Avinash C. A Catalog of the Louis and Nancy H. Dupree Collection: Afghanistan, Anthropology, Archaeology, Islamic Central Asia, Ethnology, Military History, South Asia and Related Subjects. Durham, North Carolina: Duke University, 1994
Duke University Libraries
Louis Dupree: Curriculum Vitae, 1925-1989. Peshawar, Pakistan: University of Peshawar, 1992
Duke University Libraries
Collection Overview
The Louis Dupree papers contain correspondence, notes, clippings, conference programs, drafts, manuscripts, speeches, newsletters, interview transcripts, research materials, teaching materials, a scrapbook, photographs, grant applications, memorabilia, student papers, a dissertation, and other materials related to the personal life and professional career of archaeologist, activist, and scholar Louis Dupree.
Major subjects include Louis Dupree, Nancy Hatch Dupree, the Duke University Program in Islamic and Arabian Development Studies, Ralph Braibanti, Afghanistan, Afghan refugees, Afghanistan-Pakistan relations, Pakistan, the United States Army 11th Airborne, the United States Army 187th Airborne, and the United States Military Academy at West Point. Materials range in date from 1943 to 1989. The bulk of the material is from 1980 to 1989, as Dupree had destroyed much of his correspondence and papers, because, according to Nancy Hatch Dupree, he thought they were nobody's business.
Pakistan -- Relations -- Foreign countries; Pakistan -- History -- 20th century; Refugees -- Afghanistan; Pakistan -- Social conditions -- 20th century; United States. Army. Airborne Division, 11th; Afghanistan -- History -- 20th century; United States. Army. Airborne Infantry, 187th; Afghanistan -- Relations -- Foreign; Afghanistan -- History -- Soviet occupation, 1979-1989; Scrapbooks; Anthropology -- Study and teaching (Higher); Afghanistan -- Social life and customs -- 20th century; Humanitarian assistance, American -- Afghanistan; Archaeology -- Field work; Braibanti, Ralph J. D.; Duke University -- Faculty; Duke University. Islamic and Arabian Development Studies; Dupree, Louis, 1925-; Dupree, Nancy Hatch; United States Military Academy -- Faculty
- Correspondence, 1961-1989 (bulk 1980-1989)
  - Professional and Personal Correspondence, 1961-1989
    Scope and Contents note
    Primarily professional correspondence from the last decade of Dupree's life. Dupree often developed friendships with his professional associates, so much of the professional correspondence contains personal information and vice versa. Dupree also filed notes, clippings, and other materials related to the correspondent in the same folder as the correspondence.
    Arrangement note
    Arranged alphabetically by correspondent except for two folders, one of miscellaneous correspondence and one of various letters of reference for Dupree, filed at the end of the series.
    - Ahmed, Akbar S., 1981-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - al-Masry, Abdullah, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Ali, S. Hadi Raza, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Ansary, Mir Tamim, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bethell, Nicholas, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Carrell, Laurent F., 1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Davis, Richard, 1977-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Dudley-Rowley, Marilyn, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Elmi, Sayed M. Y., 1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Emadi, Hafizulla, 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Esposito, John L., 1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Fairservis, Walter A., 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Farhadi, A. G. Ravan, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Fischer, Klaus, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Fox, Miguel Jose Hagerty, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Froz, Wahid, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Gankovsky, Yuri, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Goodwin, Peter, 1980-1988 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Gowlett, John A. J., 1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Hart, David M., 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Heath, Jennifer, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Heritage Foundation, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Indiana University: Archives of Folk and Primitive Music, 1961-1972, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Indiana University Archives of Traditional Music, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Jacobson, Jerome, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Jan Alam, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Keegan, John, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Kellogg, William W., 1985 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Khalevinski, Igor, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Khalilzad, Zalmay, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Khan, Rana Zaffarullah, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Khanazov, Anatoly M., 1987 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Lageman, Tye, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Levy, Jack S., 1985 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Mataxis, Ted, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Miskingatz, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Muslim, The (newspaper), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Naby, Eden, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Nagler, Michael N., 1984 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Narain, A. K., 1985 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Niazi, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Non-Aligned Third World, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Olesen, Asta, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Oleson, Lynn, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Pennsylvania State University, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Richter, William L., 1987 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Rigsbee, Arnold, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Rubin, Barnett R., 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Saudi Arabia, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Scarborough, Jared, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Solecki, Rose M., 1986 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Thomas, Lowell, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - University of Michigan, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Veggeberg, Kermit R., 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Walsh, Lawrence, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Weller, Richard, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Whitteridge, Gordon, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Who's Who, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Williams, Stephen, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Yousaf, Shaheer, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Zia ul-Haq and Government of Pakistan, 1977-1987 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Letters of recommendation regarding Louis Dupree, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 63)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Personnel information restricted until 2058.
  - Correspondence with Afghan and Pakistani refugees and students, 1980-1989, undated (Box 1, Folder 64-76)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Access restricted. Subseries contains sensitive information. Contact Research Services for access: https://duke.qualtrics.com/jfe/form/SV_8fblaT2NbgbQujj
- Conferences, Seminars, and Workshops, 1981-1989, undated
  Conference programs and schedules, correspondence relating to Dupree's attendance at various conferences and seminars, draft and published versions of presentations given at conferences, and Dupree's working notes for presentations.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Afghanistan: A Threatened Culture, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Afghanistan Relief Committee, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Australian National University: Soviet Withdrawal from Afghanistan, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Boston University: Center for Defense Journalism, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Bundestag: Six Years of War and Occupation in Afghanistan, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies: Pakistan and Southwest Asia Security Conference, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies: War in Afghanistan and the Plight of the Afghan Family, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - CEREDAF, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Columbia University: Pakistan in the 1980s, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Columbia University: Approaches to Islam in Central and Inner Asian Studies, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Defense Intelligence College: Afghanistan and Soviet Strategies for the Muslim World, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Duke University Islamic and Arabian Development Studies: Refugees in the Islamic World, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Foreign and Commonwealth Office: Afghanistan: The Way Forward, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Foreign Policy Research Institute, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Harvard, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Harvard: Islam and Politics in the Contemporary Muslim World, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - International Medical Corps, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - International Parliamentary Group for Human Rights in the Soviet Union, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - International Research and Exchanges Board (IREX), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - MEI, undated (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - MESA, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Middle East Studies Association, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - New York Conference on Asian Studies, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Orkand Corporation: Afghan Refugees Conference, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Oslo: Second International Afghanistan Hearing, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - Oxford, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - Princeton Center of International Studies: Conference on Inner Asia, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - SASASAAS: Southern Atlantic States Association for Asian and African Studies, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - SERMEISS, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - University of Miami: US-Soviet Rivalry in Afghanistan and the Persian Gulf, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - University of North Carolina: Afghanistan: Implications and Ramifications of Soviet Withdrawal, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - University of South Carolina: Institute of International Studies, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - University of Texas at Austin, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - University of Wisconsin: Identity Problems in Central Asia, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - University of Wisconsin: Conference on South Asia, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - University of Wisconsin: Conference on South Asia, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - University of Wisconsin: South Asian Archaeology, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - U.S. Department of State, 1981, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - Villanova, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - World Affairs Council, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - York University: The Global Crisis in Refugee Migration, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 117)
- Organizations and Committees, 1964-1989, undated
  Primarily correspondence, clippings, notes, memos, minutes, newsletters, and other materials related to organizations and committees to which Dupree belonged or in which he had an interest. Includes some writings by Dupree and his testimony before the Congressional Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Congressional Task Force on Afghanistan. Also includes notes by Dupree concerning his possible appointment as the US ambassador to Bangladesh.
  - Afghanistan Action Committees, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - Afghanistan Documentary Movie Project, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 119)
  - American Council for the Study of Islamic Societies, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 120)
  - American School of Archaeology in Pakistan, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 121)
  - Bangladesh, Ambassador to, undated (Box 2, Folder 122)
  - CASCON, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 123)
  - Comitato aiuto profughi Afgani (Italian Refugee Committee), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 124)
  - Committee for a Free Afghanistan, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 125)
  - Congress of the United States: Committee on Foreign Affairs: Subcommittee on Asian and Pacific Affairs, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 126)
  - Congressional Task Force on Afghanistan: Hearing on Effective Public Diplomacy, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 127)
  - Corning Museum of Glass, 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 128)
  - Esso, 1964-1973, undated (Box 2, Folder 129)
  - Federation for American Afghan Action, 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 130)
  - Intergovernmental Committee for Migration, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 131)
  - International Bank for Reconstruction Development, undated (Box 2, Folder 132)
  - Mule Pool, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - National Committee for Human Rights in Afghanistan, 1987-1988, undated (Box 2, Folder 134)
  - National Security Archive, 1988, undated (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - North Carolina Afghan Refugee Fund, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 136)
  - Universities Field Staff International, undated (Box 2, Folder 137)
  - Writers Union of Free Afghanistan, undated (Box 2, Folder 138)
- Writings and Research, 1947-1989, undated
  Notes, drafts, and typescripts of articles and books written by Dupree, plus other research materials.
  - Afghanistan
    Arranged chronologically
    - Princeton University Press: Afghan Interviews, 1955-1956, undated (Box 2, Folder 139)
      Transcripts of interviews with Afghans, used as research material in Dupree's book Afghanistan.
    - Princeton University Press, 1961-1981 (Box 2, Folder 140)
      Correspondence, notes about typos and other corrections and revisions, research notes, contracts, clippings, and other materials related to the publication of Afghanistan.
  - Other Writings and Research, 1947-1989, undated
    Arranged alphabetically
    - AF Forum, undated (Box 2, Folder 141)
      Typescripts of Review: Rambo III by Dupree and The Afghan Kirghiz in Turkey by Nancy Hatch Dupree.
    - Afghanistan 1989: A Turning Point in History?, undated (Box 2, Folder 142)
    - Afghanistan 2000 AD: The Worst Possible Scenario, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 143)
    - Afghanistan: The Revolution is Now!, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 144)
    - Archaeology Clippings and Notes, 1964-1986, undated (Box 2, Folder 145)
    - Australian Relief Committee for Afghan Refugees: Calendar, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 146)
      Translations of captions to calendar illustrations by Dupree.
    - Babrak, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 147)
      Letter regarding Dupree's entry for Babrak Karmal in the 1987 Encyclopedia of World Biography, plus a copy of the article.
    - Badwan Ethnography, undated (Box 2, Folder 148)
    - Bernard-Bathtub: Report on Talks with Agha Mohammad Rahmani and Mohammad Azam: 4 August 1975 (Box 2, Folder 149)
      Typescript regarding a bronze sarcophagus and related items found in Kandahar.
    - Christian Science Monitor, clippings and letters, 1980-1988 (Box 2, Folder 150)
    - Comments on Afghanistan's Political Future, undated (Box 2, Folder 151)
    - Commonweal, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 152)
    - Drafts, undated (Box 2, Folder 153)
    - Economist, letter, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 154)
    - Experiment in Democracy, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 155)
    - Folklore, undated (Box 2, Folder 156)
    - Fossil Man, circa 1970 (Box 2, Folder 157)
    - Freedom Medicine, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 158)
      Handwritten notes for a talk entitled What is Anthropology?
    - From Whence Cometh Pasta?, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 159)
    - Modest Proposal: With Apologies to Jonathan Swift, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 160)
    - Mujahidin, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 161)
    - Nation, undated (Box 2, Folder 162)
    - New York Times,, letters, 1984-1988 (Box 2, Folder 163)
    - Norwegian article, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 164)
      Xerox of article (in Norwegian) regarding Dupree and Nancy Hatch Dupree.
    - North Carolina Newspapers, letters and clippings, 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 165)
    - Pacific News Service, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 166)
      Typescript and handwritten draft of short article by Dupree regarding Soviet withdrawal from Afghanistan.
    - Poetry, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 167)
    - Police photos of P. M. Maiwandwal's suicide by hanging, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 168)
      Warning: Graphic Material
      Black and white photographs. Note by Nancy Hatch Dupree: Police photos of P. M. Maiwandwal's 'suicide by hanging' on 20 October 1973. L. D. persuaded the government not to release them as 'proof' of suicide, bec. he found them unconvincing. To my knowledge they were never published or released.
    - Refuge: Canada's Periodical on Refugees, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 169)
      Correspondence regarding Dupree's role as guest editor of the journal.
    - Research Notes on Political Parties in Pakistan, 1979, and Afghanistan, 1983, Notes, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 170)
    - The Role of the Geneva Talks, undated (Box 2, Folder 171)
    - Swedish Committee for Afghanistan: Round-Table Discussion on the Present Situation in Afghanistan, undated (Box 2, Folder 172)